Arath Velazquez

Full Stack Developer

About

Software developer with bachelor's degree in Computer Science.

Strong background in Node.js, MongoDB, AWS infrastructure and FrontEnd technologies.

About 12 years of experience in IT area and in last 6 years I have been focused on Web development. Recently, I've been working in Ecommerce projects and mainly creating first class APIs with MEAN stack and AWS infrastructure.

Technical Skills



Work Experience

Columbia

Full Stack Developer & AWS Tech Lead (Dec 2018 - Present)

Accountable for implementation of microservices and RESTful APIs running in AWS with Lambda (Node.js), Dynamo, S3, CloudWatch, CloudFormation, SES, JWT, OKTA, Swagger and MongoDB (Atlas).

Most recently, I have been involved in all the aspects of development and also provide production support, analysis, feature enhancements, mentoring, unit testing and code reviews.

As Tech Lead, I work closely with the entire AWS team, Architects, Product Owners, Business Analysts, DevOps and SFCC team to integrate our endpoints, jobs and tasks.



Senior Full Stack Developer (Dec 2015 - Dec 2018)

During this period, I worked for two different companies as freelance and then I started working fulltime for one of these. I was the main developer for a startup called MediaHunter and also I was working remotely as Node.js (MEAN) developer for a company based on Seattle and in February 2018 I started working fulltime with them.

For both companies, I performed most of the development and created Ecommerce platforms with Node.js, Angular, Bootstrap, Material Design, ElasticSearch and MongoDB.

I also performed all the implementation for database and web servers by using independent VPS and did the integration of different services and API's such as Google Maps, Mandrill for transactional emails, DigitalOcean, Google Cloud among others.



Full Stack Developer (Oct 2017 - Feb 2018)

Worked as Full Stack for MediaShift (AdTech Platform Solution) to create a dashboard by using Mongo, Node.js and React.js stack.





Software Engineer (Aug 2012 - Oct 2017)

For DexOne, I was involved in development for DexKnows and third parties services integration such Google Maps, OpenTable, among other APIs. Worked for the first time with MongoDB only for comments section and also first time with Splunk and Apache Solr.

For AT&T, I was part of the data team and worked for backend services and internal tools.



Unix Developer (Jul 2011 - Aug 2012)

Worked as Unix Developer for Bank of America.

Application development and support for backend, data migration and infrastructure. Working mainly with shell scripting, WebSphere and created internal applications.

NORDSTROM

Software Engineer (Oct 2010 - Jul 2011)

Worked for Nordstrom account providing application development mostly for Unix tools and support.



Embedded Software Engineer (Nov 2017 - Oct 2010)

Worked for Texas Instruments, specifically with Linux team to flash and work with new features for OMAP3 and OMAP4 processors.

IBM

Software Engineer (Jul 2006 - Jan 2007)

Internship in last year of career.

Member of the first pilot program to work directly with IBM for 6 months. IBM and Universidad de Colima had an agreement to integrate students to this new program and after some interviews from IBM employees, only 10 students were selected.

Education

Universidad de Colima

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science (2004 - 2007).

MongoDB University

M101JS - MongoDB for Node is Developers (Oct 2016)

M202JS - MongoDB for Javascript Developers (Sep 2019)